Hannibal 지난 이야기
Previously on Hannibal.
- 애비게일이 닉 보일을 죽였어요
- 누구에게도 말해선 안됩니다
Abigail Hobbs killed Nick Boyle.
We can tell no one.
당신이 걱정이군요, 윌
I'm worried about you, Will.
잭이 하도 살인범을
강조해서 그런지
You empathize so completely
with the killers Jack Crawford
당신은 살인범과 전적으로
공감대를 형성하고 있어요
has your mind wrapped around
that you lose yourself to them.
뇌 스캔이라도
받아야겠어요
Maybe I should
get a brain scan.
- 아직도 불안정한거야?
- 문제 있습니까, 윌?
- Do you feel unstable?
- Is there a problem, Will?
- 시간개념이 없군요
- 뭔가 잘못됐어요
- You lost time.
- There's something wrong
전 당신 친구잖습니까
with me.
I'm your friend, Will.
당신이 구한 이들은 관심 밖이니
제게 신경쓰이는건 당신뿐입니다
I don't care about the lives you
save; I care about your life,
현실과 너무
동떨어져 있어요
and your life is separating
from reality.
제 온 신경이
I can feel my nerves
롤러코스터 톱니처럼
딸각거리고 있어요
clicking like, uh,
roller coaster cogs,
피할 수 없는 긴 낙하를
위해 끌어올려지고 있죠
pulling up to the inevitable
long plunge.
소리가 빠르면
빨리 끝나는 법이죠
Quick sounds, quickly ended.
애비게일이 보일을
끝내버렸죠
Abigail Hobbs ended
Nicholas Boyle.
풍선을 터트리듯
Like a burst balloon.
목숨을 빼앗았죠
She took a life.
당신도 그랬을텐데요
You've taken a life.
네, 박사님도 그렇죠
Yeah. Yeah, so have you.
비탄에 빠졌군요. 그동안
빼앗아 온 삶들이 아니라
You're grieving, Will.
Not for the life you have taken,
당신이 뺏겨버린 삶때문에요
but for the life that was taken
from you.
애비게일이 아버지의
공포를 뒤로 한채
If Abigail could have
started over, left the horror
새출발할 수 있다면
당신도 할수 있습니다
of her father behind,
so could have you.
광기와 살인으로 뒤엉킨
스스로를 풀어내 보세요
You could untangle yourself
from the madness and the murder.
우리의 거짓말은
그녀를 위한겁니다
We lied for her.
생명을 빼앗는것은
비현실적이죠
We both know the unreality
of taking a life.
사람이 죽을 때는
다른 선택권이 없을때죠
The people who die
when we have no other choice,
그 순간만큼 그들은
단지 살점이 아닌
we know in those moments
they are not flesh,
빛이며,
but light,
공기며, 색깔인겁니다
and air, and color.
그건 살아있다는게 아닐까요?
Isn't that what it is
to be alive?
살아있음을 느낍니까, 윌?
Do you feel alive, Will?
단지...
I...
희미해지는 느낌이에요
I feel like I'm fading.
시간 감각이 둔해지거나
Have you experienced
any further loss of time?
환각이 보이는건요?
Or hallucinations?
시계 문자판을
그려보시죠
I'd like you to draw
a clock face.
숫자를 넣는겁니다
Numbered.
긴 바늘은 시간,
작은 바늘은 분이에요
Large hand indicating the hour,
small hand the minute.
왜죠?
Why?
일종의 연습이죠
An exercise. I want you
보다 현재에 집중해보세요
그리고 가능한 한 자주
to focus on the present moment.
The now. Often as you can,
언제, 어디에 있는지
떠올려 보세요
think of where you are,
and when.
본인이 누구인지도요
Think of who you are.
오후 7시 16분,
Seven sixteen PM.
메릴랜드 볼티모어,
I'm in Baltimore, Maryland.
제 이름은 윌 그레이엄
And my name is Will Graham.
간단하게 떠올릴수 있죠
A simple reminder.
현실을 의지하게 해주는
일종의 손잡이에요
The handle to reality
for you to hold on to.
살아있음도 느끼게 되죠
And know you're alive.
한글자막 by 클라투
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
무슨 일이 있던겁니까?
What happened in there?
- 혼란스럽네요
- 저도 봐서 압니다만
- I got confused.
- I've seen you confused
이런 적은 처음이군요
and I've seen you upset, but I've
never seen you afraid like this.
두려움은 익숙한 편이니
떨쳐낼 수 있을겁니다
Well, I'm an old hand at fear.
I can manage this one.
잠시 갈피를 못잡았지만
다시 돌아갈수 있습니다
I just got disoriented.
I can go back in.
그 방에서 나왔을때
당신 표정을 봤습니다
I saw the look on your face
when you came out of that room.
거기서 뭘 봤길래 갑자기
Now, what did you experience
in there that's got you mute
- 말수가 적어진겁니까?
- 전 두려워지면
all of a sudden?
I can see
시각과 청각이 예민해지죠
단지... 간결하게
and hear better afraid.
I-I just can't...
- 말할 수 없을 뿐이죠
- 윌, 당신은
...speak as concisely.
Will, you
현장을 오염시킨겁니다
이런 적은 없었는데요
contaminated the crime scene.
You've never done that before.
제 책임인것 같군요
I thought I was responsible
for it.
무슨 말씀이죠? 안에서
그 여자를 죽인겁니까?
What are you saying? You thought
that you killed that woman in there?
- 가끔은, 음, 제가 하는...
- 당신이 해야하는건
- Sometimes with, uh, what I do...
- What you do
범죄현장의 모든 증거를
유효하게 만드는 것이죠
is you take all of the evidence
available at a crime scene.
당신이 추정해서
범죄자의 사고를
You extrapolate.
You reconstruct
재현하는것 아닙니까
the thinking of a killer.
스스로를 살인자로
받아들이진 마세요
You don't think of yourself
as the killer.
재현 과정에서
정신을 잃었을뿐이에요
I got lost
in the reconstruction.
아주 잠시,
눈 깜짝할 사이죠
Just for a second. Just a blink.
관심의 대상이 되는건
원치 않으시겠지만
I know you don't like to be
the cause for concern, but I am
- 공식적으로 걱정이 되는군요
- 공식적이요?
officially concerned about you.
Officially?
네, 그래요
- Yes, that's right.
- Hm.
저를 지켜보는 이유를
생각해 봤습니다
I thought the reason
you had me seeing.
렉터 박사는 FBI
정신의가 아니니
Dr. Lecter and not an FBI
psychiatrist is
제 정신 상태 역시...
so my mental well-being stays...
못미덥다는거겠죠
unofficial.
단지 조심하고
싶을 뿐입니다
I just want
to be careful with you.
당신이 여기서
무너져서는 안됩니다
We don't want
to break you here.
그런겁니까?
다 저 때문인가요?
Is that what's happening?
Have I broken you?
망가진 저보다
Do you have anyone
더 나은 정상적인
사람이 있던가요?
that does this better unbroken
than I do broken?
공포때문에 무례해졌군요
Fear makes you rude, Will.
이름은 베스 르보,
자기 피에 익사했군요
She drowned on her own blood.
그나마 남은 피는
온통 바닥과
And what she didn't drown on
is all over the floor
침대밑에 뿌려졌어요
숨으려고 했겠군요
and under the bed.
She was trying to hide from him.
끌고 들어간거죠. 범인은
침대밑에서 기다린겁니다
He dragged her there. He was
waiting under the bed for her.
격투끝에 간신히
빠져나왔겠어요
Fought to claw her way out.
안면이 있었을거에요
걱정하던 사람이었죠
He knew her.
Someone who cared about her,
- 그렇게 생각했거나요
- 걱정이 지나쳤군요
- or thought he did.
- He cared too much.
그럼 남자친구나,
예전 남자친구,
So, we're looking
for boyfriends, ex-boyfriends,
혹은 동료를 찾아야겠군
coworkers,
- 장을 봐줄 정도였으니
- 지문 하나가 나이프
the guy who bags her groceries.
I've got a clean
손잡이에 남아있네요
아마 당신거겠죠
set of prints on the knife
handle. I assume they're yours.
미안합니다
- Sorry.
- Mm.
범인의 것으로 보이는
표피조직도 남아있지만
There's other dermal tissue,
presumably from the killer's,
피부가 너무 망가져서
쓸만한 지문은 없는데요
but the skin is so diseased
or damaged it didn't leave
희생자는 손톱에
조직이 남을만큼
any useful prints. The victim scratched
her killer deep enough to pile
깊게 할퀴었지만
혈흔은 없어요
tissue under the fingernails,
but never drew blood.
왜 피가 남지 않았을까?
Why didn't he bleed?
피해자의 얼굴에
상처를 낸 후에
After he cut up
the victim's face,
피부를 벗겨내려고
한 것 같은데요
it looks like he was trying
to pull her skin back.
마스크를 벗기듯
말인가요?
Like he was removing a mask?
아직도 손에서...
I still have the...
피의 *쇠 냄새가 나요
coppery smell of blood
on my hands.
그녀를 죽이기 전의,
I can't remember seeing
현장의 기억이 없어요
the crime scene before I saw
myself killing her.
기억들이 무의식속으로
가라앉았지만
Those memories sank
out of sight,
여전히 그 부재는
인식하고 있군요
yet you're aware
of their absence.
제가 상상했던 폭력에는
어떤 웅장함이 있었어요
There's a grandiosity
to the violence that I imagined
제가 알고있는것보다
현실적이었거든요
that feels more real
than what I know is true.
알고 있는건 뭡니까?
What do you know to be true?
전 죽이지 않았어요
그랬을리가 없죠
I know I didn't kill her.
I couldn't have.
하지만 그녀를 난자한것과
죽어가던 모습은 기억나요
But I remember cutting into her.
I remember watching her die.
당신은 현실을 가장한
환상을 극복해야합니다
You must overcome these delusions
that are disguising your reality.
범인이 갖고 있던
흉포한 환상은 뭐죠?
What kind of savage delusions
does this killer have?
그런게 아니라
외로움이었어요
It wasn't savage.
It was lonely.
절박했어요. 슬펐죠
It was desperate. Sad.
언뜻 거울에 비춰봤는데
I caught a glimpse of myself
in the mirror,
제 자신이 들여다 보이더군요
and I looked right through me,
속속들이 투영되다보니
마치 제가 이방인같았죠
past me, as if I was a...
was just a stranger.
당신은 한계에 대해
정직하게 맞서야해요
You have to honestly confront
your limitations
당신의 일로 말이죠
with what you do.
- 얼마나 영향을 미치든 말이죠
- 만약 제한적으로
And how it affects you.
If by limitations
제 정신과 광기의 차이를
의미한거라면 동의할 수 없습니다
you mean the difference between sanity
and insanity, I don't accept that.
- 동의하시는건 뭡니까?
- 제정신이 아니란건
- What do you accept?
- I know
저도 알고 있습니다.
하지만 그게 전부는 아니에요
what kind of crazy I am, and
this isn't that kind of crazy.
일종의... 점령같은거죠
This could be... seizures.
종양일수도 있죠
This could be a tumor.
혈전일까요?
A... a blood clot.
신경의를 추천해드리죠
I can recommend a neurologist.
생리학적인게 아니라면
정신에 문제가 있다는걸
But if it isn't physiological,
then you have to accept
받아들여야 할겁니다
what you're struggling with
is mental illness.
관리를 잘하고 계시네요
You're in very good hands.
여기 렉터 박사는 가장...
Dr. Lecter here is
- 정신이 온전한 친구일겁니다
- 동의할 수 밖에
- one of the sanest men I know.
- I would agree.
서트클리프 박사와 전
홉킨스의대에서 동고동락했죠
Dr. Sutcliffe and I were
residents together at Hopkins.
다 옛날 일이지
Another life ago,
손이 조금 더러워지는건
조금도 개의치 않았잖나
back when you weren't afraid to
get your hands a little dirty.
난 정신의 작용에
늘 이끌린거니까
I was always drawn
to how the mind works.
뇌 활동보다 그쪽이 훨씬
역동적인거란걸 발견한거지
I found it much more dynamic
than how the brain works.
영사된 상은 영사기보다
더 흥미로운 법이죠
The projected image is more
interesting than the projector,
물론 영사기가 고장나기
전까지 말입니다
until, of course,
the projector breaks down.
두통에 대해서 말인데요
So, Will, these headaches.
본격적으로 언제
시작된겁니까?
When did they begin in earnest?
2, 3개월 전이죠
Two to three months ago.
아마 윌이 현장에
About the time Will went back
복귀했을때일거네
그때 만났으니까
into the field,
which is when I met him.
환각 증세는요?
And the hallucinations?
그건 언제인지 정확히
말씀드리기 어렵네요
I can't really say
when they started.
음...
Um...
꿈이 아닐지도 모른다고
천천히 알기 시작했거든요
I just slowly became aware
that I might not be dreaming.
뇌염이군
It's encephalitis.
- 그게 자네 선 진단인가?
- 그래
- That's your pre-diagnosis?
- Yes.
근거는...?
Based on...?
냄새가 느껴지니까
I could smell it.
간호사의 향수나
구별하던 후각이
So your sense of smell has gone
from calling out a nurse's perfume
자기 면역 질환까지
진단하게 된거로군
to diagnosing
autoimmune disease.
몽유병이 시작된데다가
특유의 냄새까지 나니까
He started sleepwalking and
I noticed a very specific scent.
뇌염의 냄새는
정확히 어떤건가?
And what exactly does
encephalitis smell like?
온기가 있지
It has heat.
온기가 있는 달콤함
A fevered sweetness.
의심이 됐다면 왜 진작에
If you suspected,
why didn't you
- 말해주지 않았나?
- 확실해야 할테니까
say something?
Had to be sure.
증상은 천천히 시작해서
Symptoms began slowly
점진적으로 악화됐어
그리고 어제
and gradually worsened.
And yesterday,
시계를 그려보라고 했는데
I asked him to draw a clock.
이게 바로 그거네
This is what he drew.
공간 부주의로군
Oh. Spatial neglect.
두통, 방향 감각 상실,
Headaches, disorientation,
환각, 의식 변성(變性) 상태
hallucinations,
altered consciousness.
모두 숨길 수 없는 증세군
It's all the telltale signs.
Hm.
이런 고질적인 정신 상태의
심리적 작용은
It is so rare to be able to
study the psychological effect
공부의 기회가 드문 편이지
of this type of malady
on a person's mind.
게다가 신경학상 영향이라면
It's more rare still
더욱 보기 힘든 편이지
to be able to study
the neurological effects.
의사라면 과학적 연구의
이득을 평가해야만 하지
A doctor has to weigh the ultimate
benefit of scientific study.
현재까지도 뇌에 대해선
알려진게 거의 없으니까
Even in these times, we know
so little about the brain.
엄청난 발견이 있을거네
There are great discoveries
to be made.
뇌 우측이 온통
염증 투성이야
The right side of his brain is
completely inflamed.
반NMDA수용체 뇌염일세
It's anti-NMDA receptor
encephalitis.
증세가 악화중이었겠어
The symptoms are only going
to get worse.
나도 아네
I know.
윌에게는 안된 일이지
It's unfortunate for Will.
나한테는 냄새 안나나?
What do you smell on me?
기회
Opportunity.
이상한 부분은
발견하지 못했습니다
We didn't find anything
abnormal.
혈관성 기형이나,
No vascular malformations,
종양도 없고,
no tumors,
부종이나 출혈 등
충격의 영향도 없군요
no swelling or bleeding,
no evidence of stroke.
깨끗해요
Nothing.
신경학상으로는
문제가 없습니다
There's nothing wrong with you
neurologically.
결국 제가 겪고있는건
정신적인 부분이군요
So what I'm experiencing is
psychological.
뇌 스캔으로 정신질환까지
Well... brain scans can't
진단할 수는 없으니까요
diagnose, uh, mental disorders.
의학적 질병만
가려낼 뿐이죠
They can only rule out
medical illnesses
비근한 증세를 보이는
종양처럼 말입니다
like a tumor, which can have
similar symptoms.
몇가지 테스트를
Look, we'll run
더 진행할겁니다
some more tests.
아마 혈액샘플이
더 필요하겠지만
We'll take some more
blood samples, but I imagine
그것들로는 결론이
나진 않을것 같은데요
they'll prove to be
just as inconclusive.
아마 아셨을겁니다
You knew from the moment
강의실까지 찾아와 그를
잠재적으로 위험한 환경에
you walked into his classroom
that you were putting him
투입할때부터 말이죠
in a potentially destructive
environment.
미네소타에서 8명이 죽었어요
윌은 범인을 잡아주었죠
I had eight college girls dead in Minnesota.
Will caught their killer for me.
범인들의 질병이
옮아온겁니다
He also caught
their killer's disease.
생명을 빼앗는다는걸
떨쳐내지 못하더군요
He can't stop thinking
about what it is to take a life.
무고한 희생자가 나오느니
그가 미치는게 나을겁니다
I'd rather he go a little mad
than other innocents lose
그건 아마
그도 동의할테구요
their lives, and I think
he would feel the same way.
윌도 무고할텐데요
Will is an innocent.
네, 그렇죠
Yes. He is.
윌에게는 능력이 있어요
I mean, Will is genuine.
어떠한 일을 겪게 해도
살아남을거란 말입니다
He'll survive anything
I could put him through.
어떤 식으로든 스스로
헤쳐나왔으니까요
He will always fight his way
back to himself.
지금까지 항상
그랬던건 아니죠
Not always. So far.
오늘 의사로부터
He saw
진찰을 받고오는 길입니다
이상은 없다고 하더군요
a neurologist today. They found
nothing wrong with him.
그게 오히려
화가 나나 봅니다
He was very upset by that.
뭔가 잘못됐으면
했다는겁니까?
You're saying he wanted
something to be wrong?
그는 정신질환이
아니었으면 했거든요
I think he wanted an answer
that wasn't mental illness.
정신적으로 문제가
있다고 보는군요
You think he's mentally ill.
그에게는 *거울 뉴런이
너무 많은게 문제에요
The problem Will has is
too many mirror neurons.
우리도 어렸을땐
머리에 가득차 있었지만
Our heads are filled with them
when we are children...
사회화에 도움을 주고는
소멸해 버리거든요
supposed to help us socialize
and then melt away.
하지만 윌에게는
그대로 남아있죠
But Will held on to his,
자신을 안다는것이
도전이 된겁니다
which makes knowing who he is
a challenge.
현장에 그를 데리고 가면
When you take him
to a crime scene, Jack,
대기에는 비명소리가
스며들어 있는거죠
the very air has screams
smeared on it.
그런 곳에서라면
그대로 반사하지 않고
In those places,
he doesn't just reflect;
빨아들일겁니다
He absorbs.
오후 10시 36분,
It's 10:36.
델러웨어 그린우드,
I'm in Greenwood, Delaware.
내 이름은 윌 그레이엄
My name is Will Graham.
새벽 1시 17분
It's 1:17 AM.
우,우린 델러웨어 그린우드
W-We're in Greenwood, Delaware.
내 이름은 윌 그레이엄
And my name is Will Graham.
당신은 살아있어요
And you're alive.
내 말이 들리면
If you can hear me,
살아있는 거라구요!
you're alive!
왜 전화한거죠?
Why did you call me?
왜 잭이나 경찰에
전화하지 않구요?
Why not Jack?
Why not the police?
제가 전화드린건...
I called you because...
내가 본게 진짜인지
확신하지 못해서에요
I'm not entirely sure
what I saw was real.
그럼 증명해보죠
Then let's prove it.
팔을 움켜잡았는데...
I grabbed her arm...
죽은 피부 한거풀이
And an entire layer
of dead skin separated
장갑처럼 완전히
벗겨져 버렸어요
from the underlying tissue,
like she was wearing a glove.
- 그래서 피가 없었던거군요
- 혈액순환도 안됐겠죠
- That's why she doesn't bleed.
- Right. There's no circulation.
- 붙잡아 둘 세포가 없으니까요
- 그걸 어떻게 했죠?
And there's nothing alive in the tissue to bind it.
What did you do with it?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
기억나는거 없어요?
포도상구균 감염증일지도 모르죠
Could be
a staphylococcal infection.
- 한센병이거나요
- 눈동자가 탁하더군요
That, or leprosy.
Her eyes were discolored.
그녀는 영양실조에,
황달에 걸렸어요
She was, uh, malnourished,
jaundiced.
간이 제 기능을 못하니
그녀는...
Her liver was shutting down.
She was...
정상이 아닐거에요
deranged.
그녀가 그랬겠군요
마스크라고 생각한거에요
So she mutilated a woman's face
because she thought it was a mask.
얼굴은 볼수 없을거에요
She can't see faces.
그녀가 베스를 죽였다면
If she did kill
본인은 그랬는지조차
몰랐을거에요
Beth LeBeau, she might
not even know she did it.
그럼 왜 돌아왔을까요?
Then why did she come back?
- 자기가 안했다는걸 확인하려구요
- 이유가 그거에요?
- To convince herself she didn't.
- Is that why you came back?
그 문제는 명확하지 않지만
If I wasn't clear
on that issue,
내가 베스를 죽이지
않았다는건 알아요
I know I didn't kill
Beth LeBeau.
누가 그랬는지
알고싶은거에요
I just want to know who did.
저도 그래요
Me too.
Yeah.
당신은 수많은
억측의 대상이에요
You're the subject of a lot
of speculation at the bureau.
그래요? 어떻게들
생각하고 있죠?
Oh, yeah?
What are they speculating?
잭이 지나치게
밀어붙여서
That Jack pushed you
당신도 스스로
몰아붙인다는거죠
right up to the edge, and now
you're pushing yourself over.
그녀는...
This killer...
자신의 현실을
인정하지 못해요
can't accept her reality.
가끔은 저도
그런 편이니까요
I can occasionally identify
with that.
그렇긴하지만, 저도...
That said, I feel...
비교적 정상이겠죠
relatively sane.
오후 7시 05분
It's 7:05 PM.
메릴랜드, 볼티모어
I'm in Baltimore, Maryland.
내 이름은 윌 그레이엄
My name is Will Graham.
비위를 맞춰주니 고맙군요
Thank you for humoring me.
귀신이 보이는것 같아요
I feel like I'm seeing a ghost.
- 살인범? 아니면 본인?
- 둘다요
- Regarding this killer, or yourself?
- Both.
그녀는 진짜에요
증거가 있죠
Well, she's real. You know
she's real. There's evidence.
그녀를 발견했을때
When you found her,
분별력이 사라진게 아니에요
your sanity did not leave you.
- 시간이 문제죠
- 또 그랬습니까?
- Time did.
- You lost time again?
서트클리프 박사와
이야기 해봤습니다
I spoke to Dr. Sutcliffe.
당신의 방문에 대해
간단히 의논했었죠
We briefly discussed
the particulars of your visit.
저와 상의해 보시겠습니까?
Would you like to discuss them
with me?
특별할건 없어요. 그분도
잘못된걸 못찾았으니까요
There are no particulars.
He didn't find anything wrong.
계속 해답을 찾아보죠
Then we keep looking
for answers.
몇가지 테스트를
해봐도 괜찮겠죠
Perhaps you would permit me
to run some tests of my own.
저에 대해 책을 쓰거나
하지는 않으시겠죠
You wouldn't publish anything
about me, would you,
렉터 박사님?
Dr. Lecter?
남들에게 도움이 될만한
치료상의 가치가 있다면
If there were ever anything that might
be of therapeutic value to others,
완전히 식별하기 힘든
형태로 끌어낼겁니다
I'd abstract it in a form that
would be totally unrecognizable.
모쪼록 제 사후에
해주시면 좋겠군요
Just do me a favor
and publish it posthumously.
저 말입니까,
당신 말입니까?
After your death or mine?
누가 먼저가 됐든요
Whichever comes first.
*코타르 증후군은
고려해 봤습니까?
Have you considered
Cotard's Syndrome?
희귀한 망상장애인데
It's a rare delusional disorder
환자 스스로가
죽었다고 믿는거죠
in which a person believes
he or she is dead.
살인범 말입니까,
아님 저 말입니까
Are you talking
about the killer or me?
- 물론 살인범이죠
- 아, 물론이죠. 음,
- The killer, of course.
- Well, of course. Um,
그녀는 희생자의 얼굴을
볼 수 없었거나
she couldn't
see the victim's face.
벗거내려고 했을거에요
Or she was trying
to uncover it.
남을 알아보지 못하는건
그 증후군과 관련이 있죠
The inability to identify others
is associated with Cotard.
얼굴을 인식하는 뇌 영역과
It's a misfiring
in the areas of the brain
인식과정에 감정을 더해주는
which recognize faces,
and also in the amygdala,
편도체에서의 오류니까요
which adds emotion
to those recognitions.
가장 가까인 지인들조차
사기꾼으로 보일겁니다
Even those closest to her would
seem like imposters.
결국 자신이 사랑했거나
신뢰하던 사람들에게
So she... she reached out
to someone she loved,
손을 뻗은거군요
someone she trusted.
배신감을 느꼈으니
폭력적으로 변했겠죠
She felt betrayed,
became violent.
무엇도, 어느 누구도
신뢰할수 없는겁니다
She can't trust anything or anyone
she once knew to be trustworthy.
정신적 질환이 그렇게
내버려두지 않으니까요
Her mental illness won't
let her.
범죄현장에서의 조직 샘플이
We matched the tissue samples
from the crime scene
따님의 것과 일치하더군요
to your daughter's
***.
전화를 받았을때
오히려 안심이 되더군요
***
이제서야 발견하셨다니
그 애도...
I thought that you had found her
and she was, um...
평온을 되찾겠군요
would be at peace.
죽었을거라 보십니까?
You thought she might be dead?
저를 마치 끔찍한
엄마처럼 만드시는군요
Well, that makes me sound
like a horrible mother.
좋은 엄마가 되려고 노력했어요
I tried to be a good mom.
할 수 있는건 다 해봤어요
I tried to do everything
that I could.
- 고통이나마 없으면 했죠
- 누구도 어머님의 헌신을
I just don't want her to be in pain.
No one's doubting
의심하진 않을겁니다
메드센 부인
your dedication
to your daughter, Mrs. Madchen.
베스 르보는 잘 아셨습니까?
How well did she know
Beth LeBeau?
친한 친구들이었죠
학교도 함께 다니고,
They were best friends.
They went to school together,
애가 학교에 다니기
위험할 때 까지요
um, until it was unsafe
for Georgia to go to school.
처음 알게된건 언제였습니까?
When did you first recognize
that your daughter was
정신질환이 있는거 말입니다
struggling with mental illness?
9살때 그러더군요
When she was nine
and she told me that she was
절 죽일 생각을 했다구요
thinking about killing me
자기는 이미 죽은
몸이라고 하더군요
and said that she was
already dead.
증세는 어땠습니까
What sort of symptoms
did she have?
발작에 환각,
She had seizures,
hallucinations,
우울증 증세를 보였죠
psychotic depression.
*긴장증이라니
고마울 따름이었죠
I was grateful
when she was catatonic.
폭력적 성향이었습니까?
Was she ever violent?
가끔은요
Sometimes.
의사는 뭐라던가요?
What did her doctor say?
별말 없었어요
Not much.
병원에서 몇 달씩
머무르곤 했죠
She spent months at a time
in the hospital.
혈액 테스트에
뇌 스캔을 해봐도
Blood tests and brain scans,
결론을 내리지 못했어요
and all of them inconclusive.
They could
문제에 대한 대답을
말해주지 못했죠
never tell me what was wrong.
아직도 모르시는거군요?
And you still don't know?
계속 이랬다 저랬다
했으니까요
They would just say
it was this or it was that.
아시잖아요, 그들이 하는거라곤
You know, they were just...
늘 추측뿐이었어요
...they were just always
guessing.
그래서 제가 파고들어봤죠
And I did my own research.
의사가 하는 말과
전문용어를
I wrote down every word
that the doctors said,
모두 받아적으면서
많이 배웠죠
the different terminology.
Learned a lot.
하지만 제가 주로 배운건
But mostly what I learned is,
정신질환이 얼마나
밝혀지지 않았느냐에요
um, how little is actually known
about mental illness.
해결책을 찾기란
희박하겠더군요
All they know, it's rarely
about finding solutions.
기대나 충족시켜 주는거죠
It's just more
about managing expectations.
기대를 충족시킨다구요?
Managing your expectations?
제 기대치를 바꿔야겠죠
Changing my expectations.
미리엄 라스가 죽었을때
You know,
when Miriam Lass died,
난 짐을 꾸리러
여기 와야했습니다
I had to come back here
to this office to pack up,
하지만...
but...
가봐야한다고 생각했는데
감정을 억누르기 힘들더군요
that got to be too overwhelming.
I thought I should just leave,
훈련생을 죽인것 같아서요
seeing as how I had gotten
a trainee killed.
리더쉽이 부족하다면
그건 내 책임이죠
That lack of leadership on my
part, that was my responsibility.
당신이 죽인게 아닙니다
리퍼가 그런거지
You didn't kill Miriam Lass;
The Chesapeake Ripper did.
난 그렇지 않아요
내가 그녀를 끌어냈죠
It didn't feel that way to me.
I pulled her out of a classroom,
마치 당신을 이끈것처럼요
like I pulled you
out of a classroom.
그녀는 학생이었고
전 강사 아닙니까
She was a student;
I am a teacher.
난 그녀처럼 당신에게도
책임이 있단 말입니다
I'm still just as responsible
for you as I was for her.
- 전 제가 알아서 합니다
- 날 제외해선 곤란하죠
- I'll take my own responsibility.
- Well, not from me you won't.
우린 함께 할겁니다
미리엄때는 내가
We can do it together.
I broke the rules
규칙을 깼죠. 규칙을 깨도록
내가 바람을 넣었으니까요
with Miriam. I encouraged her
to break the rules.
지금은 당신과 함께
규칙을 깨고있는 겁니다.
I am breaking the rules with you now.
By letting
- 불안정한 요원을 투입하는거요?
- 특별 요원이죠
an unstable agent do field work?
Special agent. Oh.
당신은 FBI를 대표하고
날 대신하는겁니다
That means you represent
the FBI. You still represent me.
내가 당신을 대신했다구요?
Have I misrepresented you,
Jack?
아뇨, 아뇨. 하지만 날
궁금하게 만드는군요
No, no.
But you have me curious.
왜 아직도 여기 있죠?
이 일이 안좋다는건 둘다
Why are you still here
when the both of us know
뻔히 아는데 말이죠
that this is bad for you?
- 그만뒀으면 좋겠습니까?
- 아니
- Do you want me to quit?
- No.
그만둘 기회는 드렸습니다
No, you had an opportunity
to quit.
당신이 걷어찼죠
왜 그랬습니까?
You didn't take it.
Why not?
제 생각을 말씀드리죠
지금 맡고있는 일이
Let me tell you what I think.
I think that the work
당신에게 안정감을
부여하고 있는거죠
you do here has created a sense
of stability for you.
안정감은 당신에게도
좋은 일이겠죠
Stability is good
for you, Will.
안정감에는 튼튼한
토대가 필요해요
Stability requires
strong foundations, Jack.
- 제 *계류장은 모래위에 지어졌죠
- 난 모래가 아닙니다
(배를 대어 놓는 장소)
My moorings are built on sand.
I'm not sand.
난 암반이란 말입니다
I am bedrock.
스스로에 대해 의심이 들면
When you doubt yourself,
나 역시 의심할
필요가 없습니다
you don't have to doubt me too.
골드베르크 변주곡
13변주, by JS 바흐
Variation 13, by JS Bach)
*이베리코 하몽이네
(흑돼지)
The Jamon Iberico.
늘 진귀한 접대를
좋아했지, 그렇지?
Still love your little rare
treats, don't you, Hannibal?
얻기 비싸고 어려울수록
더 좋은 법이니까
The more expensive and difficult
they are to obtain, the better.
최고를 기대하게
만드는 차이랄까
It's a distinction that adds
an expectation of quality.
- 늘 그런건 아니지
- 이베리코는 다르지
- Not always.
- Well, for Iberico,
매년 몇천마리만 엄선되지
only a few thousand are selected
each year.
하지만 그래봐야 돼지야
But is the pig,
살찌워, 도살되고,
그늘에서 말려지면
once fattened and slaughtered
and air-cured,
다른 돼지보다
정말 우수한걸까?
really superior
to any other pig?
아니면 단지
Or is it simply a matter of
평판에 관한 문제일까?
reputation preceding product?
자네 참 엉뚱하군
It's irrelevant.
먹는 사람이 훌륭하다면
If the meat-eater thinks
it's superior,
그 믿음이 가치를 결정하지
then belief determines value.
심리학이 신경학보다
우선하는 케이스겠군
- A case of psychology overriding neurology.
- So, we know
이베리코는 그렇다치고
how Iberico gets his pigs.
자넨 환자를 어떻게 얻나?
How did you get yours?
윌 그레이엄 말인가?
Are you referring
to Will Graham?
자넨 세련된걸 좋아하잖나
We know you're fond
of the rarified.
그가 왜 그리 특별한거지?
What makes him so rare?
윌은 놀랄만큼 생생한
상상력을 갖고 있지
Will has a remarkably vivid
imagination.
아름답지
Beautiful.
순수한 감정이입
Pure empathy.
그가 이해하지 못하는건 없지
그것때문에 두려울테고
Nothing he can't understand,
and that terrifies him.
그의 정신을 흥분시켰군
So you set his mind on fire.
상상력이란 흥분에 대한
흥미로운 촉매제거든
Imagination is an interesting
accelerant for a fever.
얼마나 진행시킬 셈인가?
So... how far does this go?
불을 끌건가, 아니면
Do you put out the fire,
타버리도록 내버려둘텐가?
or do you let him burn?
그는 내 친굴세
Will is my friend.
필요하다면 불을 꺼야겠지
We will put out the fire
when it's necessary.
테스트를 몇건 더 요구하더군
He has asked for more tests.
이제 우리는 뭔지
확실히 알았으니
Now that we have confirmed
what it is,
그에게서 숨어버리는건
한결 손쉬워질거네
it'll be easier to hide
from him.
귀에 끼시죠
You put these in.
순식간에 끝날겁니다
This'll be over
before you know it.
서트클리프 박사님?
Dr. Sutcliffe?
깨끗해요
You're clean.
뭔가 묻히지 않고
일을 끝낼순 없었겠죠
You couldn't have done this
without getting something
아무것도 없어요
on you, and there's nothing
on you.
제 기분은 그렇지않아요
I don't feel clean.
베스의 집에서 발견된
질병 조직과 결손 조직이
The murder weapon has the same sort of
diseased or damaged tissues that we found
흉기에서 검출됐습니다
다른 희생자들과
at Beth LeBeau's house.
What's this guy got to do
어떤 연관성이 있을까요?
with the other victim?
제가 문제에요
Just me.
기억나는게 뭡니까?
What do you remember?
여기로 와서,
I remember coming here,
MRI 검사를 받고,
다시 나와서,
going into the MRI,
getting out,
서트클리프 박사의
시체를 발견한거죠
and, uh, finding
Dr. Sutcliffe's body.
- 혼란스럽진 않습니까?
- 음, 제가 알기로는요
- No confusion?
- Well, not that I'm aware of.
서트클리프 박사에겐
흔한 일이었을까요?
Was your Dr. Sutcliffe
in the habit
혼자 남아 환자를
진찰하는거 말입니다
of seeing patients after-hours when
he's the only one in the office?
서글서글한 분이었어요
He was very accommodating.
조지아 메드센이
당신을 미행한 후,
Georgia Madchen
followed you here,
MRI 검사를 받는 동안
and while you're ticking away
in the MRI,
이런 짓을 한거로군요
she does this to your doctor.
- 왜 그일까요?
- 그녀는 얼굴이 안보여요
Why him?
She can't see faces.
아마 저라고 생각했겠죠
Maybe she thought he was me.
좋습니다, 수사중인데
왜 하필 당신일까요?
All right, while we're at it,
why you?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
제가 유기견을
거두곤 하거든요
I have a habit
of collecting strays.
그녀를 본 그날밤에
제가 그녀에게 말했죠
I-I-I told her, tried
to tell her the night I saw her,
그녀가 살아있다고 말하고
싶었어요. 그때 들었겠죠
I tried to tell her she was
alive. Maybe she heard me.
한동안 그런 일이
없었는지도 모르죠
Maybe that hadn't occurred
to her in a while.
당신이 보여요, 조지아
I see you, Georgia.
당신이 누군지 떠올려봐요
Think of who you are.
지금은 자정
It's midnight.
당신은 버지니아,
울프 트랩에 있어요
You're in Wolf Trap, Virginia.
이름은 조지아 메드센
Your name is Georgia Madchen.
혼자가 아니에요
You're not alone.
우린 함께 있으니까요
We are here together.
제가 살아있다구요?
Am I alive?
회복될까요?
She'll recover?
감염의 가능성이 높습니다
체액 대부분을 잃었으니까요
Risk of infection is high.
She's lost most of her vital fluids.
골 질량도 그렇습니다
Even some bone mass. She's being
화상 피해자처럼
치료받을 겁니다
treated like a burn victim.
정신은 돌아오겠죠?
But she'll recover mentally?
코타르 증후군이에요
이런 망상의 환자들은
She has Cotard's Syndrome.
Almost all sufferers
대부분 치료로
회복 가능합니다만
of this delusion recover
with treatment...
이런 극단적인 케이스는
전기 충격 요법이 필요하죠
in extreme cases like this one,
electroconvulsive therapy.
오히려 윌이 더 걱정이군요
I'm more concerned about Will.
동료인 서트클리프 박사를
더 걱정했을줄 알았는데요
I thought you'd be more concerned
about your colleague, Dr. Sutcliffe.
그를 애도하는건 사실이지만
I am grieving Dr. Sutcliffe,
윌은 적어도 살아있으니까요
but Will is very much alive.
정상으로 돌아갈수 있다는
해답을 절박하게 구하고 있죠
He's still desperate for an explanation
that can make everything right again.
오히려 절박한건
이쪽 같은데요
I'm, uh, pretty desperate
for some explanations myself.
그녀가 깨어나면
대화를 나눠야겠습니다
I really want to talk to this
young woman when she comes to.
얼마나 기억할거라고
보십니까?
How much do you think
she'll remember?
저도 바라는 부분이지만
많은걸 기억하진 못할겁니다
Well, I sincerely hope, for her
sake, she doesn't remember much.
한글자막 by 클라투
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
> GOOD EVENING. A 17-YEAR-OLD
BOY IS PRESUMED TO HAVE